现在，我们已经拥有了通过改变局部状态进行对象建模的力量，我想我们应该找点复杂的东西来演示一下这种力量是多么强大
假设，我们处在这样一个物理系统中，系统中的事物驱动彼此，全部的这些事物组成了世界
每一个事物都有其独立的局部状态
这决定了它属于一个事物
这个模型存在于我们的大脑里，当然它也可以存在于计算机中
我要做的是，把真实世界中事物，相应地在计算机中建立对象，真实世界中事物的联系，相应地在计算机建立对象间的关系，对象与关系与现实世界的事物与联系一一对应
这也就指引了我们如何去模块化
如果我们真的把世界想象成这样，由许多小的事物组成，我们就可以一一对其建模，这样就把世界的模块性传递到了我们的程序这中
这就是面向对象编程的原理所在
我所见过的最完美的对象
非常非常完美，那就是电气系统。电气系统真的是物理学家构造的非常非常好的一种对象
这里我有一些机器零件
确实是机器零件
有一个电线连接起了零件的两个部分
电气世界中有一个非常棒的特性，就是我可以说这是一个对象，这是一个对象，这两个对象连接起来，所有关系一目了然
而且，如果我没有用电线连接，它们便没有关系
比如我有一个灯泡，一个已经接在插座上的电源
关系非常明了
没有另外的关系表现形式
就算我把电线打个结，灯仍然是亮着的
没什么影响
在物理上，这种连接可以被抽象出来，至少在低频状态下是可以的
而且这就是全部的连接方式了
当然，我们来进一步讨论一种在电气系统中最为广泛的抽象，数字电路
这有一些对象元件
例如，在数字电路里我们有像非门这样的东西
还有与门
或门
我们用电线把它们连接起来，电线就是对01信号的抽象
我们不关心具体的物理因素，像电压啊，电流啊，元件怎么组合啊 等等
这些因素统一抽象为信号
我们用电路连接元件，构建系统
一会儿我要向你们介绍一种新的语言，像之前讲过的图形语言一样，都嵌入在LISP中，不是昨天那种模式匹配替换的语言
模式匹配替换的语言还需要用LISP编写另外的程序来解释
但是之前那种绘图语言我们可以随意使用，不管构造过程还是组合数据
举例来说，首先我要有一些原子对象，比如这个，这个
然后用电线去组合它们
(make-wire)构造一个电线
a就代表了一根电线
b也是
c也是
d也是
还有e
还有s
再来看元件，或门有两个输入a和b，一个输出d，就像这样
与门，a和b两个输入，一个输出c
就像这样来声明，我可以组合出任意的电路
我已经说明了原子元素，组合方法，然后就轮到抽象方法了
举例来说，这是一个半加器
如果你学过电路设计肯定知道这个东西
输入两个数a和b，输出“和”和进位
事实上，完全可以用我刚刚说的来组合电路
把半加器看成一个盒子，盒子的边界，抽象出的永远都是一个盒子
从盒子里引出A B S C四根线
这些是已经声明了的变量，我们就用它们来定义半加器
为了连接半加器里面的线路，我构造了电线D和E，E是这个，D是这个，内部连接的线路并没有引出盒子之外，就像这样连起来
你可以看的出来，这个语言非常有层次性
如果一个语言没有层次性，如果你不能把一个复合对象当成原子对象来使用，这个语言肯定是有问题的 -- 至少我这样觉得
之前我们都是从计算一些数字上的函数开始的，现在我们不那样做，我们从一些电路对象开始，构建更多的电路对象
用LISP里的lambda将其粘合起来
lambda是很有用的粘合剂
当然，两个半加器可以组成结构更为复杂的全加器，就像这里这个，把线路连在一起，还需要另外的电线如S，C1和C2，还有一个或门。全加器输入两个数，一个进位值，输出“和”和一个进位值
除此之外，还可以把全加器链起来组成更大的加法器
现在我们的语言有了原子元素，组合方法和抽象方法，才算完整
现在问题来了，如何实现这套语言？
其实并不难
首先来看原子元素
实现原子元素也是整个问题的根本所在
至于组合方法与抽象方法完全不用亲自实现，因为语言嵌入在LISP中可以直接使用LISP中的这种机制
好的，我们先来看一个原子元素
非门吧
非门有两个引脚，一个输入，一个输出
有信号输入的时候它要做点什么
它和输入的电线说 -- 我们开始讨论一些关于对象的东西，细节之处以后再谈 -- 它需要对作为输入的电线的说 “当你的值变的时候，告诉我一声”
所以非门可能会这样和这个输入对象交流， “Hi，我是George”
“我的工作就是，当你变化的时候对结果做一点修改”
“所以当你变化的时候，告诉我一声”
“因为我需要这个去做点别的”
我们在这里为in添加一个动作invert-in，它在这里定义，是一个无参数的过程，对线路上的信号取反
在一段延时之后，就是inverter-delay -- 每个电路对象都有延时 -- 我们再把输出设置为新的值
非常简单
你可以这样理解，这个作为输出的电线很有灵性，当信号改变的时候，它就奔走相告
“我的值已经改变啦”
所以当你把非门和与门或者其它的什么连在一起的时候，其中会有很多类似“奔走相告”的过程，确保信号以正确的方式传递
到了这里反而很平常
logical-not只是把0，1换成1，0罢了
与门就相对复杂一些
与门有两个输入A1，A2，输出是output
但是其结构和非门没有什么大的不同
当输入信号改变的时候，就执行过程and-action
它所做的只是根据信号逻辑与运算出输出信号而已
在and-gate-delay的延时之后，更新输出信号值
我完全是按愿望思考来完成的这一切
你看，这里有一个赋值操作
并不是set!
之前我们模仿过CAR，CDR构建新过程，这里也是同理，按照惯例，它的具体实现留作最后的惊喜
这个过程add-action!，提醒线路A1，当它改变的时候记得执行过程add-action-procedure，A2也是一样
非常简单
现在我们再来聊聊各个部分之间信息是如何传递的吧
假设，有一个非常简单的电路，一个与门，输入a，b，输出端c又作为输入接在非门上，非门的输出是d
一个对实际电路的抽象
要不了几分钱就可以从Radio Shack买到这些元件
那些元件的作用和画在这里的差不多，不同的是元件上面都标有很多小数字像“LS04”之类的
现在来看其中的计算模型
它联系起我们头脑里的现实和在计算机中虚拟的现实，这种联系到底是什么
真实世界的对象或关系改变了，我就去改变“虚拟”世界中相对应的对象或关系
这是我们的目标
让我们来看看怎么做
这一团东西代表信号A
A，一个信号
画的像一团云
再画另一个信号，B
这两个信号将要一起连入一个盒子，一个与门，一个动作过程
这就是与门的动作过程
它又联系起另一个信号C，后面的非门连接起来和前面差不多
最后一个信号/电线，D
整体布局就是这样
现在必须来研究它们内部的实际机制了，它们的实际运行过程
每一个电线都必须知道自己的信号是什么
所以内部一定有些变量来表示信号
a有一个变量，signal
也不要忘了它所关联的环境
剩下的每一个都和a一样
这里也有一个signal变量
可以猜出来，signal的值不是0就是1
还需要一个列表，记录一些“联系人”，当信号实际改变的时候要去通知”他们“
我们得通知这个与门
这个列表我们叫它AP(Action Procedures，动作过程)
假定它真的用列表实现，在这里，列表里第一个肯定是这个与门
b和a一样
也可能有一些其它“人”在时刻等待着A来叫“他们”
所以这里可能有其它“人”，具体不知道是谁
我画在这里
在b内部的AP列表里，肯定也要有这个与门
相类似的，这里这样来连接
这是c要通知的“人”
d也一样
但是我不知道它要通知谁，因为“他们”没有在我的图中出现
可能是和D连接起来的其它门吧
假如与门被“人”通知了 -- 因为"其它人"信号值的变化 -- 与门就得回头去检测自己的输入电路的新值是多少，才能做“与”操作，生成新的输出信号
这也即与门的输入，A1是这个a，A2就是b
不只这样，还有点别的
还有一个输出
同样地，非门也有一个输入，它也不时地在关注着信号的变化，当有“人”来通知它“我已经改变了”
它就反过来查询这个新的信号值
取到值之后，然后计算输出，改变输出的信号值
等等等等，就像是这样
因此我也必须有这么多的连接
现在我们回头观察一下，这个与门
这张幻灯片
这几个部分的内容
对每个与门，都有A1，A2两个输入，一个输出output
当and-gate运行的时候，A1 A2 output构成了其运行“环境”，它们有各自的信号值
在这个环境下，我构建一个新的过程
and-action-procedure
过程定义了并没有实际运行
当它运行的时候，根据环境模型
找到它的局部环境
and-action-procedure就取到了这里的A1 A2 output的值
A1 A2 output
我们还没有深入探索“电线”的内部结构
我们来看看
来看看“电线”
非常棒的结构
“电线”是有那么一点复杂
哦，说错了
是非常复杂
但是还是来看一下，到底是什么
“电线”是这上面画的云一样的东西
有两个主要部分，都是它的状态
其中一个是信号值
换句话说，当我们执行make-wire，首先要做的是新建两个局部变量signal和action-procs
在这个上下文中，我们定义了一系列的过程
先看(set-my-signal! new)
它所做的只是，取一个新值new
如果new和signal一样，信号没有变化，就没必要做什么了
否则，把signal的值赋值为new，再执行action-procs里的所有过程，即通知所有“相关的人”
当作为and-gate的参数的时候，它就是我的“联系人”了，得去通知它
添加“联系人”的这个过程在最下面
然后，我还得定义一个接受动作过程的过程，就在这里，使用con把新的过程与原来的过程列表连接在一起，再赋值予action-pros，最后还要再运行一次这个过程proc
这是一种事件驱动的模拟模型，我还不打算细讲，因为那还需要思考更多的内容
最后定义一个过程dispatcher，用来解读传递给线路的信息，执行不同的操作，比如这里，当前的信号值是多少？
设置新信号值的方法是什么？
我想要这个方法
我怎么样去添加另外的动作过程呢？
最后，返回过程dispatch
因此整个电线的被构建成了一个可接受不同信息的对象，比如 ‘add-action!来询问添加动作过程的方法是什么？
因此实际上，它返回了一个过程，这个过程接收一个动作过程作为参数，将其实际添加入电线的action-procs的列表中
这是一种权限
给予你了一种去改变自身动作过程列表的权限
再来看看这里
下一张幻灯片
噢
没什么有意思的
(call-each procedures)只是对列表中过程顺序地执行调用，没什么好说的
我们早就知道了
然而，如果我想知道线路上的信号值是多少，就得这样来询问wire
wire只是一个dispatch过程而已
只是一个过程
这是是‘get-signal作为参数来执行这个过程
实际得到的只是取得线路信号值的方法
进一步的就可以得到信号值
如果我想要对线路设置一个新的信号值，这里传递wire和new-value两个参数，(wire 'set-signal!)取得改变线路信号的权限，实际是一个过程，应用于new-value
我们继续追溯这个过程，调用(wire 'set-signal)之后，我们返回这个过程，定义在线路里面，名为set-my-signal，我们回头看幻灯片，返回的过程有一个实际的调用，以new-value为参数，去改变线路内部signal变量的值，最后再去依次通知“联系人”
非常简单
再来看看幻灯片，还有最后一点，add-action!，我想你们很轻易地就理解了
wire action-proc两个参数
然后请求添加动作过程的权限
得到权限去添加新的动作过程
这就是整个“电线”对象
还有些细节
比如，我怎么来控制它？
这些延时怎么实现？
我们来快速过一遍
下一张
我们来看看
我们细看与门或者或门定义，会发现里面还有“延时”这样的东西
一段延时之后才开始执行过程，改变输出
这个要如何实现？
这里引入一种新技巧，非常复杂，我们得非常细心地来看
在“delay”的延时之后，执行过程action
"delay"是一个数字，"action“是一个过程
这里有一个特殊的数据结构the-agenda，用于组织时间与动作过程
一会儿再来细看它
先把这里说完
the-agenda记录下来一个动作过程未来执行的时间
在current-time + delay段的时间之后，将会执行那个过程
这个过程随着计算好的这个时刻，添加入the-agenda中
要使这个”计时钟表“运行起来并不困难
下面这个过程progagate，就是来做这件事的
如果the-agenda是空的，就没有要做的
否则，我们就取出the-agenda的第一个元素，它是一个没有参数的过程
这里有两层括号
里面的一层返回一个过程，外面的一层括号执行了这个过程
就是之前存储入the-agenda的动作
然后这个过程就可以从the-agenda删掉了，最后执行propagate，进行无限循环
这就是整体的结构
还有点其它的
一会儿再来看the-agenda
现在整体上来看
Well, in order to set this thing going, I just want to show you some behavior out of this simulator.
By the way, you may think this simulator is very simple, and probably too simple to be useful.
The fact of the matter is that this simulator has been used to manufacture a fairly large computer.
So this is a real live example.
Actually, not exactly this simulator, because I'll tell you the difference.
The difference is that there were many more different kinds of primitives.
There's not just the word inverter or and-gate.
There were things like edge-triggered, flip-flops, and latches, transparent latches, and adders, and things like that.
And the difficulty with that is that there's pages and pages of the definitions of all these primitives with numbers like LS04.
And then there's many more parameters for them.
It's not just one delay.
There's things like set up times and hold times and all that.
But with the exception of that part of the complexity, the structure of the simulator that we use for building a real computer, that works is exactly what you're seeing here.
Well in any case, what we have here is a few simple things.
Like, there's inverter delays being set up and making a new agenda.
And then we can make some inputs.
There's input-1, input-2, a sum and a carry, which are wires.
I'm going to put a special kind of object called a probe onto, onto some of the wires, onto sum and onto carry.
A probe is a, can object that has the property that when you change a wire it's attached to, it types out a message.
It's an easy thing to do.
And then once we have that, of course, the way you put the probe on, the first thing it does, it says, the current value of the sum at time 0 is 0 because I just noticed it.
And the value of the carry at time 0, this is the time, is 0.
And then we go off and we build some structure.
Like, we can build a structure here that says you have a half-adder on input-1, input-2, sum, and carry.
And we're going to set the signal on input-1 to 1.
We do some propagation.
At time 8, which you could see going through this thing if you wanted to, the new value of sum became 1.
And the thing says I'm done.
That wasn't very interesting.
But we can send it some more signals.
Like, we set-signal on input-2 to be one.
And at that time if we propagate, then it carried at 11, the carry becomes 1, and at 16, the sum's new value becomes 0.
And you might want to work out that, if you like, about the digital circuitry.
It's true, and it works.
And it's not very interesting.
But that's the kind of behavior we get out of this thing.
So what I've shown you right now is a large-scale picture, how you, at a bigger, big scale, you implement an event-driven simulation of some sort.
And how you might organize it to have nice hierarchical structure allowing you to build abstract boxes that you can instantiate.
But I haven't told you any of the details about how this agenda and things like that work.
That we'll do next.
And that's going to involve change and mutation of data and things like that.
Are there any questions now, before I go on?
Thank you.
Let's take a break.
Well, we've been making a simulation.
And the simulation is an event-driven simulation where the objects in the world are the objects in the computer.
And the changes of state that are happening in the world in time are organized to be time in the computer, so that if something happens after something else in the world, then we have it happen after, after the corresponding events happen in the same order in the computer.
That's where we have assignments, when we make that alignment.
Right now I want to show you a way of organizing time, which is an agenda or priority queue, it's sometimes called.
We'll do some--we'll do a little bit of just understanding what are the things we need to be able to do to make agendas.
And so we're going to have--and so right now over here, I'm going to write down a bunch of primitive operations for manipulating agendas.
I'm not going to show you the code for them because they're all very simple, and you've got listings of all that anyway.
So what do we have?
We have things like make-agenda which produces a new agenda.
We can ask--we get the current-time of an agenda, which gives me a number, a time.
We can get--we can ask whether an agenda is empty, empty-agenda.
And that produces either a true or a false.
We can add an object to an agenda.
Actually, what we add to an agenda is an operation--an action to be done.
And that takes a time, the action itself, and the agenda I want to add it to.
That inserts it in the appropriate place in the agenda.
I can get the first item off an agenda, the first thing I have to do, which is going to give me an action.
And I can remove the first item from an agenda.
That's what I have to be able to do with agendas.
That is a big complicated mess.
From an agenda.
Well, let's see how we can organize this thing as a data structure a bit.
Well, an agenda is going to be some kind of list. And it's going to be a list that I'm going to have to be able to modify.
So we have to talk about modifying of lists, because I'm going to add things to it, and delete things from it, and things like that.
It's organized by time.
It's probably good to keep it in sorted order.
But sometimes there are lots of things that happen at the same time--approximate same time.
What I have to do is say, group things by the time at which they're supposed to happen.
So I'm going to make an agenda as a list of segments.
And so I'm going to draw you a data structure for an agenda, a perfectly reasonable one.
Here's an agenda.
It's a thing that begins with a name.
I'm going to do it right now out of list structure.
It's got a header.
There's a reason for the header.
We're going to see the reason soon.
And it will have a segment.
It will have--it will be a list of segments.
Supposing this agenda has two segments, they're the car's-- successive car's of this list. Each segment is going to have a time--  say for example, 10-- that says that the things that happen in this segment are at time 10.
And what I'm going to have in here is another data structure which I'm not going to describe, which is a queue of things to do at time 10.
It's a queue.
And we'll talk about that in a second.
But abstractly, the queue is just a list of things to do at a particular time.
And I can add things to a queue.
This is a queue.
There's a time, there's a segment.
Now, I may have another segment in this agenda.
Supposing this is stuff that happens at time 30.
It has, of course, another queue of things that are queued up to be done at time 30.
Well, there are various things I have to be able to do to an agenda.
Supposing I want to add to an agenda another thing to be done at time 10.
Well, that's not very hard.
I'm going to walk down here, looking for the segment of time 10.
It is possible that there is no segment of time 10.
We'll cover that case in a second.
But if I find a segment of time 10, then if I want to add another thing to be done at time 10, I just increase that queue-- "just increase" isn't such an obvious idea.
But I increase the things to be done at that time.
Now, supposing I want to add something to be done at time 20.
There is no segment for time 20.
I'm going to have to create a new segment.
I want my time 20 segment to exist between time 10 and time 30.
Well, that takes a little work.
I'm going to have to do a CONS.
I'm going to have to make a new element of the agenda list--list of segments.
I'm going to have to change.
Here's change.
I'm going to have to change the CDR of the CDR of the agenda to point that a new CONS of the new segment and the CDR of the CDR of the CDR of the agenda, the CD-D-D-DR.
And this is going to have a new segment now of time 20 with its own queue, which now has one element in it.
If I wanted to add something at the end, I'm going to have to replace the CDR of this, of this list with something.
We're going to have to change that piece of data structure.
So I'm going to need new primitives for doing this.
But I'm just showing you why I need them.
And finally, if I wanted to add a thing to be done at time 5, I'm going to have to change this one, because I'm going to have to add it in over here, which is why I planned ahead and had a header cell, which has a place.
If I'm going to change things, I have to have places for the change.
I have to have a place to make the change.
If I remove things from the agenda, that's not so hard.
Removing them from the beginning is pretty easy, which is the only case I have. I can go looking for the first, the first segment.
I see if it has a non-empty queue.
If it has a non-empty queue, well, I'm going to delete one element from the queue, like that.
If the queue ever becomes empty, then I have to delete the whole segment.
And then this, this changes to point to here.
So it's quite a complicated data structure manipulation going on, the details of which are not really very exciting.
Now, let's talk about queues.
They're similar.
Because each of these agendas has a queue in it.
What's a queue?
A queue is going to have the following primitive operations.
To make a queue, this gives me a new queue.
I'm going to have to be able to insert into a queue a new item.
I'm going to have to be able to delete from a queue the first item in the queue.
And I want to be able to get the first thing in the queue from some queue.
I also have to be able to test whether a queue is empty.
And when you invent things like this, I want you to be very careful to use the kinds of conventions I use for naming things.
Notice that I'm careful to say these change something and that tests it.
And presumably, I did the same thing over here.
OK, and there should be an empty test over here.
OK, well, how would I make a queue?
A queue wants to be something I can add to at the end of, and pick up the thing at the beginning of.
I should be able to delete from the beginning and add to the end.
Well, I'm going to show you a very simple structure for that.
We can make this out of CONSes as well.
Here's a queue.
It has--it has a queue header, which contains two parts-- a front pointer and a rear pointer.
And here I have a queue with two items in it.
The first item, I don't know, it's perhaps a 1.
And the second item, I don't know, let's give it a 2.
The reason why I want two pointers in here, a front pointer and a rear pointer, is so I can add to the end without having to chase down from the beginning.
So for example, if I wanted to add one more item to this queue, if I want to add on another item to be worried about later, all I have to do is make a CONS, which contains that item, say a 3.
That's for inserting 3 into the queue.
Then I have to change this pointer here to here.
And I have to change this one to point to the new rear.
If I wish to take the first element of the queue, the first item, I just go chasing down the front pointer until I find the first one and pick it up.
If I wish to delete the first item from the queue, delete-queue, all I do is move the front pointer along this way.
The new front of the queue is now this.
So queues are very simple too.
So what you see now is that I need a certain number of new primitive operations.
And I'm going to give them some names.
And then we're going to look into how they work, and how they're used.
We have set the CAR of some pair, or a thing produced by CONSing, to a new value.
And set the CDR of a pair to a new value.
And then we're going to look into how they work.
I needed setting CAR over here to delete the first element of the queue.
This is the CAR, and I had to set it.
I had to be able to set the CDR to be able to move the rear pointer, or to be able to increment the queue here.
All of the operations I did were made out of those that I just showed you on the, on the last blackboard.
Good.
Let's pause the time, and take a little break then.
When we originally introduced pairs made out of CONS, made by CONS, we only said a few axioms about them, which were of the form-- what were they-- for all X and Y, the CAR of the CONS of X and Y is X and the CDR of the CONS of X and Y is Y. Now, these say nothing about whether a CONS has an identity like a person.
In fact, all they say is something sort of abstract, that a CONS is the parts it's made out of.
And of course, two things are made out of the same parts, they're the same, at least from the point of view of these axioms.
But by introducing assignment-- in fact, mutable data is a kind of assignment, we have a set CAR and a set CDR-- by introducing those, these axioms no longer tell the whole story.
And they're still true if written exactly like this.
But they don't tell the whole story.
Because if I'm going to set a particular CAR in a particular CONS, the questions are, well, is that setting all CARs and all CONSes of the same two things or not?
If I--if we use CONSes to make up things like rational numbers, or things like 3 over 4, supposing I had two three-fourths.
Are they the same one-- or are they different?
Well, in the case of numbers, it doesn't matter.
Because there's no meaning to changing the denominator of a number.
What you could do is make a number which has a different denominator.
But the concept of changing a number which has to have a different denominator is sort of a very weird, and sort of not supported by what you think of as mathematics.
However, when these CONSes represent things in the physical world, then changing something like the CAR is like removing a piece of the fingernail.
And so CONSes have an identity.
Let me show you what I mean about identity, first of all.
Let's do some little example here.
Supposing I define A to the CONS of 1 and 2.
Well, what that means, first of all, is that somewhere in some environment I've made a symbol A to have a value which is a pair consisting of pointers to a 1 and a pointer to a 2, just like that.
Now, supposing I also say define B to be the CONS--  it doesn't matter, but I like it better, it's prettier-- of A and A.
Well, first of all, I'm using the name A twice.
At this moment, I'm going to think of CONSes as having identity.
This is the same one.
And so what that means is I make another pair, which I'm going to call B. And it contains two pointers to A. At this point, I have three names for this object.
A is its name.
The CAR of B is its name.
And the CDR of B is its name.
It has several aliases, they're called.
Now, supposing I do something like set-the-CAR, the CAR of the CAR of B to 3.
What that means is I find the CAR of B, that's this.
I set the CAR of that to be 3, changing this.
I've changed A. If I were to ask what's the CAR of A--of A now?
I would get out 3, even though here we see that A was the CONS of 1 and 2.
I caused A to change by changing B.
There is sharing here.
That's sometimes what we want.
Surely in the queues and things like that, that's exactly what we defined our--organized our data structures to facilitate-- sharing.
But inadvertent sharing, unanticipated interactions between objects, is the source of most of the bugs that occur in complicated programs. So by introducing this possibility of things having identity and sharing and having multiple names for the same thing, we get a lot of power.
But we're going to pay for it with lots of complexity and bugs.
So also, for example, if I just looked at this just to drive that home, the CADR of B, which has nothing to do with even the CAR of B, apparently.
The CADR of B, what's that?
Take that CDR of B and now take the CAR of that.
Oh, that's 3 also.
So I can have non-local interactions by sharing.
And I have to be very careful of that.
Well, so far, of course, it seems I've introduced several different assignment operators-- set, set CAR, set CDR. Well, maybe I should just get rid of set CAR and set CDR. Maybe they're not worthwhile.
Well, the answer is that once you let the camel's nose into the tent, the rest of him follows.
All I have to have is set, and I can make all of the--all of the bad things that can happen.
Let's play with that a little bit.
A couple of days ago, when we introduced compound data, you saw Hal show you a definition of CONS in terms of a message acceptor.
I'm going to show you even a more horrible thing, a definition of CONS in terms of nothing but air, hot air.
What is the definition of CONS, of the old functional kind, in terms of purely lambdic expressions, procedures?
Because I'm going to then modify this definition to get assignment to be only one kind of assignment, to get rid of the set CAR and set CDR in terms of set.
So what if I define CONS of X and Y to be a procedure of one argument called a message M, which calls that message on X and Y?
This [? idea ?] was invented by Alonzo Church, who was the greatest programmer of the 20th century, although he never saw a computer.
It was done in the 1930s.
He was a logician, I suppose at Princeton at the time.
Define CAR of X to be the result of applying X to that procedure of two arguments, A and D, which selects A. I will define CDR of X to be that procedure, to be the result of applying X to that procedure of A and D, which selects D.
Now, you may not recognize this as CAR, CDR, and CONS.
But I'm going to demonstrate to you that it satisfies the original axioms, just once.
And then we're going to do some playing of games.
Consider the problem CAR of CONS of, say, 35 and 47.
Well, what is that?
It is the result of taking car of the result of substituting 35 and 47 for X and Y in the body of this.
Well, that's easy enough.
That's CAR of the result of substituting into lambda of M, M of 35 and 47.
Well, what this is, is the result of substituting this object for X in the body of that.
So that's just lambda of M-- that's substituted, because this object is being substituted for X, which is the beginning of a list, lambda of M-- M of 35 and 47, applied to that procedure of A and D, which gives me A. Well, that's the result of substituting this for M here.
So that's the same thing as lambda of A, D, A, applied to 35 and 47.
Oh, well that's 35.
That's substituting 35 for A and for 47 for D in A. So I don't need any data at all, not even numbers.
This is Alonso Church's hack.
Well, now we're going to do something nasty to him.
Being a logician, he wouldn't like this.
But as programmers, let's look at the overhead.
And here we go.
I'm going to change the definition of CONS.
It's almost the same as Alonzo Church's, but not quite.
What do we have here?
The CONS of two arguments, X and Y, is going to be that procedure of one argument M, which supplies M to X and Y as before, but also to two permissions, the permission to set X to N and the permission to set Y to N, given that I have an N.
So besides the things that I had here in Church's definition, what I have is that the thing that CONS returns will apply its argument to not just the values of the X and Y that the CONS is made of, but also permissions to set X and Y to new values.
Now, of course, just as before, CAR is exactly the same.
The CAR of X is nothing more than applying X, as in Church's definition, to a procedure, in this case, of four arguments, which selects out the first one.
And just as we did before, that will be the value of X that was contained in the procedure which is the result of evaluating this lambda expression in the environment where X and Y are defined over here.
That's the value of CONS.
Now, however, the exciting part.
CDR, of course, is the same.
The exciting part, set CAR and set CDR. Well, they're nothing very complicated anymore.
Set CAR of a CONS X to a new value Y is nothing more than applying that CONS, which is the procedure of four--the procedure of one argument which applies its argument to four things, to a procedure which is of four arguments-- the value of X, the value of Y, permission to set X, the permission to set Y-- and using it--using that permission to set X to the new value.
And similarly, set-cdr is the same thing.
So what you've just seen is that I didn't introduce any new primitives at all.
Whether or not I want to implement it this way is a matter of engineering.
And the answer is of course I don't implement it this way for reasons that have to do with engineering.
However in principle, logically, once I introduced one assignment operator, I've assigned--I've introduced them all.
Are there any questions?
Yes, David.
AUDIENCE: I can follow you up until you get--I can follow all of that.
But when we bring in the permissions, defining CONS in terms of the lambda N, I don't follow where N gets passed.
PROFESSOR: Oh, I'm sorry.
I'll show you.
Let's follow it.
Of course, we could do it on the blackboard.
It's not so hard.
But it's also easy here.
Supposing I wish to set-cdr of X to Y. See that right there.
set-cdr of X to Y. X is presumably a CONS, a thing resulting from evaluating CONS.
Therefore X comes from a place over here, that that X is of the result of evaluating this lambda expression.
Right?
That when I evaluated that lambda expression, I evaluated it in an environment where the arguments to CONS were defined.
That means that as free variables in this lambda expression, there is the--there are in the frame, which is the parent frame of this lambda expression, the procedure resulting from this lambda expression, X and Y have places.
And it's possible to set them.
I set them to an N, which is the argument of the permission.
The permission is a procedure which is passed to M, which is the argument that the CONS object gets passed.
Now, let's go back here in the set-cdr The CONS object, which is the first argument of set-cdr gets passed an argument.
That--there's a procedure of four things, indeed, because that's the same thing as this M over here, which is applied to four objects.
The object over here, SD, is, in fact, this permission.
When I use SD, I apply it to Y, right there.
So that comes from this.
AUDIENCE: So what do you-- PROFESSOR: So to finish that, the N that was here is the Y which is here.
How's that?
AUDIENCE: Right, OK.
Now, when you do a set-cdr, X is the value the CDR is going to become.
PROFESSOR: The X over here.
I'm sorry, that's not true.
The X is--set-cdr has two arguments-- The CONS I'm changing and the value I'm changing it to.
So you have them backwards, that's all.
Are there any other questions?
Well, thank you.
It's time for lunch.